MEHDI AYOUB

Full Stack Developer

**** 00971527175267

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mehdi-ayoub-6b1485243/

- @ ayoub.mehdi@outlook.com
- https://github.com/mehdi-ayoub



SUMMARY

Full-Stack Developer with an experience in Data analysis and Al. I recently graduated from Le Wagon's intensive Web Development boot camp and am currently pursuing a professional Diploma in Data Analysis and Al. My educational background includes a bachelor's degree in Electrical and Electronics Engineering. I'm dedicated to delivering innovative solutions and driving excellence in web development projects.

EDUCATION

06/2023 - 09/2023

Web Development

France, Paris

Le Wagon

- · 9- week full-time intensive coding boot-camp
- Developed proficiency in programming languages including Python, Ruby, JavaScript, HTML and CSS
- Conceived, developed, and presented the project 'EcoWheels,' during a coding boot-camp. This innovative web application calculates the distance between shipments and automatically computes CO2 emissions for each shipment

08/2023 - NOW

Beirut, Lebanon

Professional Diploma in Artificial Intelligence and Data Science
American University of Beirut

· Developed proficiency in tools and languages such as Python, R, automation, database management and SQL.

09/2015 - 09/2019

Dubai, UAF

Bachelor of Science in Electrical and Electronics Engineering Al Ghurair University

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

08/2023 - Present

Web Developer Intern

Dubai, UAE

TEXTPERTOS Technology Services

- · Collaborated with senior developers on the design, development, and maintenance of over 20 responsive websites
- Successfully integrated 5 third-party services and APIs
- Managed and optimized a MySQL database for our client portal containing 10,000+ records, improving query performance and ensuring data integrity

01/2023 - 06/2023

Customer Support Representative

Dubai, UAE

Clemenceau Medical Centre Dubai

- Utilized Electronic Medical Record (EMR) system to process patient payments and reconcile accounts receivables, leading to a significant 20% decrease in billing errors on average
- Assessed extensive data related to more than 30,000 patients across various clinics and different specialties to identify opportunities for improvement, resulting in a 10% increase in patient satisfaction scores

07/2021 - 12/2022

Technical Support Agent

Dubai, UAE

American Hospital Dubai

- Coordinated with higher operations management, advertisement team, and clinic managers to identify and target specialties that increased patient flow and satisfaction, resulting in a 15% boost in patient appointments within six months
- Developed and implemented billing policies and procedures that improved revenue cycle efficiency and reduced billing errors to less than 3%

12/2015 - 07/2021

Data Analysis Controller

Dubai, UAE

Roads and Transport Authority

- Proposed more than 30 solutions to improve LYNX system efficiencies and implemented those solutions to improve the company's programs
- Collaborated with external partners, including Cisco, Emircom, and Software AG, to deliver the Smart Fleet Management System project. The initiative resulted in a notable 5% reduction in accidents, aligning with the management's targeted safety improvements

SKILLS

Ruby on Rails HTML **CSS Javascript** Node.js business intelligence containers Git software development Github **Full Stack** Tableau **Pvthon** performance analysis WebGL Responsive web design Front-end

KNOWLEDGEABLE SKILLS

NoSQL PostgreSQL WordPress Kanban Scrum AWS gulp React.js Java Ember.js